Fatherland is a drama, thriller, action film directed by Christopher Menaul.
Fictional account of what might have happened if Hitler had won the war.
It is now the 1960s and Germany's war crimes have so far been kept a secret.
Hitler wants to talk peace with the US president.
An American journalist and a German homicide cop stumble into a
plot to destroy all evidence of the genocide.
SS-Sturmbannführer Xavier March, played by Rutger Hauer.
Charlie Maguire, played by Miranda Richardson.
SS-Oberstgruppenführer Artur Nebe, played by Peter Vaughan.
SS-Untersturmführer Max Jäger, played by Michael Kitchen.
Anna von Hagen, played by Jean Marsh.
General Globus, played by John Shrapnel.
Fatherland is a 1994 American alternate history mystery-thriller film directed by Christopher Menaul, written by Stanley Weiser
and Ron Hutchinson, and starring Rutger Hauer, Miranda Richardson, Peter Vaughan, Jean Marsh and Michael Kitchen.
Based on the 1992 novel by Robert Harris, the film is set in an alternate 1960s Germany still
under Nazi control, and concerns a murder investigation of Party officials.
The film premiered on HBO on November 26, 1994.
It received mixed reviews, but was a commercial success.
Miranda Richardson won a Golden Globe Award for Best Actress – Miniseries or Television Film, while the film was also nominated
for Best Limited or Anthology Series or Television Film and Best Actor – Miniseries or Television Film (for Hauer).
The film explores themes of journalist, nazi, ss (nazi
schutzstaffel), holocaust (shoah), murder hunt.
The tone is emotional and intense.